<idea-plugin>
    <id>com.maxapp.branchknife</id>
    <name>Git Branch Knife</name>
    <vendor>jinxinfuture</vendor>

    <description><![CDATA[
<h2>Git Branch Knife — Split a Giant Git Branch into Focused PRs</h2>

<p>
Working in a <b>monorepo</b>? Made changes across multiple services in one branch?
<b>Git Branch Knife</b> lets you visually split your Git branch changes into multiple focused,
reviewable pull requests — one per service or module — directly inside IntelliJ IDEA.
</p>
<p>
No more giant PRs that touch 10 services at once. No more reviewers saying "this is too big to review."
</p>

<h3>The Problem It Solves</h3>
<p>
You're on <code>feature/cross-service-update</code> and your changes span <code>payment-service</code>,
<code>order-service</code>, and <code>auth-service</code>. To get proper code reviews, you need three
separate branches and PRs — but creating them manually is tedious and error-prone.
Git Branch Knife does it in one click.
</p>

<h3>How It Works</h3>
<ol>
  <li>Trigger <b>Slice by Service</b> from the <b>Git menu</b>, <b>Tools → Git Branch Knife</b>, or right-click a branch in the Git Log.</li>
  <li>Your changed files appear in a tree on the left.</li>
  <li>Branch target cards are auto-created on the right — one per service, based on your <code>branch-knife.paths</code> config.</li>
  <li>Adjust assignments if needed, then click <b>Execute Split</b>.</li>
</ol>

<h3>Key Features</h3>
<ul>
  <li><b>Visual branch splitter</b> — See all changed files and assign them to target branches with a clear card-based UI.</li>
  <li><b>Auto-detection</b> — Automatically groups files by service using a simple path config file (<code>branch-knife.paths</code>).</li>
  <li><b>Unassigned file tracking</b> — Files not yet assigned to any branch are highlighted red in the left tree. Collapsed directories also turn red so nothing slips through.</li>
  <li><b>Smart branch naming</b> — New branches are named <code>{current-branch}-{service}</code>, e.g. <code>feature/my-work-payment-service</code>.</li>
  <li><b>Hierarchical file tree</b> — Files inside each card are shown as a collapsible tree, not a flat list.</li>
  <li><b>Move all files</b> — Bulk-move all files from one card to another in one click; the empty card is removed automatically.</li>
  <li><b>Keyboard support</b> — Press <kbd>Delete</kbd> / <kbd>⌫</kbd> to remove selected files or whole directory groups from a card.</li>
  <li><b>Right-click context menu</b> — Move single files or entire directories to another branch target.</li>
  <li><b>Zero IDE restart</b> — Edit <code>branch-knife.paths</code> and re-open the dialog; changes take effect immediately.</li>
  <li><b>English / Chinese UI</b> — Toggle language in the top-right corner of the dialog.</li>
</ul>

<h3>branch-knife.paths — Path Config Format</h3>
<pre>
# path-prefix=branch-name, one rule per line
apps/payment-service=payment-service
apps/order-service=order-service
apps/auth-service=auth-service
# multiple paths → one branch:
apps/order-service/school=school-service
</pre>
<p>Files not matching any rule go into an <b>Others</b> card for manual assignment.</p>

<h3>Entry Points</h3>
<ul>
  <li><b>Git menu → Slice by Service…</b></li>
  <li><b>Tools → Git Branch Knife → Slice by Service…</b></li>
  <li><b>VCS Operations popup</b> (<kbd>Alt+`</kbd>)</li>
  <li>Right-click a branch in the <b>Git Log</b> branch panel</li>
  <li><b>Find Action</b> (<kbd>⌘⇧A</kbd> / <kbd>Ctrl+Shift+A</kbd>) → <code>Slice by Service</code></li>
</ul>
<p>No default shortcut — bind one in <b>Settings → Keymap → Git Branch Knife</b>.</p>
    ]]></description>

    <change-notes><![CDATA[
<h3>0.1.2</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Fixed binary incompatibility with IDEA 2024.3 and 2025.1 (GitBranchActionsUtil API changes)</li>
  <li>Replaced deprecated UIUtil.getSeparatorColor() and GitRepository.getGitDir()</li>
</ul>

<h3>0.1.1</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Added plugin icon</li>
  <li>Bug fixes and UI polish</li>
</ul>

<h3>0.1.0</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Smart PR Splitter dialog with visual branch target cards</li>
  <li>Hierarchical path tree view inside each card</li>
  <li>Unassigned file tracking with red highlights in the left file tree</li>
  <li>Move-all-files action with automatic source card removal</li>
  <li>Delete key support for removing paths from cards</li>
  <li>Directory-level deletion (removes all files under a dir)</li>
  <li>Row hover highlight via alpha compositing</li>
  <li>Smart branch naming based on current branch + service name</li>
  <li>branch-knife.paths: unmatched files go to a single Others card (no further splitting)</li>
  <li>Right-click context menus for move and remove</li>
</ul>
    ]]></change-notes>

    <depends>com.intellij.modules.platform</depends>
    <depends>Git4Idea</depends>

    <actions>
        <action id="com.maxapp.branchknife.SliceAction"
                class="com.maxapp.branchknife.SliceAction"
                text="Slice by Service..."
                description="Split current branch changes into multiple focused branches by service path">
            <add-to-group group-id="Git.Branch" anchor="last"/>
            <add-to-group group-id="Git.Menu" anchor="last"/>
            <add-to-group group-id="Vcs.Operations.Popup" anchor="last"/>
        </action>
        <group id="com.maxapp.branchknife.ToolsMenuGroup"
               text="Branch Knife"
               description="Split monorepo branches by service path"
               popup="true">
            <add-to-group group-id="ToolsMenu" anchor="last"/>
            <reference ref="com.maxapp.branchknife.SliceAction"/>
        </group>
    </actions>
</idea-plugin>
